# Tyler Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | http://tyler.engineering

# Summary

Software engineer with 5+ years experience in development and design. Most of my recent work has been focused on building backend systems, including but not limited to infrastructure, APIs and microservices, and client/server systems; including the development of the frontend client side.

# Experience

### Amazon.com, Inc., Seattle, WA

#### Dec. 2019 - Present

# Software Development Engineer, Alexa Personality

- Work on the development of a client/server system, used by Alexa content creators. Includes a frontend in Javascript with React, and a backend in Kotlin.
- Developed, and continuously maintain, an infrastructure pipeline to house the team's related software services as they grow. Used a new internal framework to build it, with the testing portion of the framework solely my responsibility to research, develop, test, and implement.
- Involved in the team's two week oncall rotation, with responsibilities including fixing tickets cuts by other teams using our software, providing general maintenance to our systems if anything breaks, and being a general point of contact of the team.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS stack, Javascript, React Framework, Kotlin, Git.

# Cockroach Labs, New York, NY

# May 2019 - Sep. 2019

# Software Engineer, Bulk I/O

- Apart of the Bulk I/O team, which is responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

#### Dataminr, New York, NY

September 2018 - February 2019

#### Software Engineer, Content Search

- Work on developing the tools used to search and filter through the Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java. Applications ran on AWS, and much of the day to day work involved use with the AWS tech stack. Kinesis was used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration amongst them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

#### **IBM Corporation**, Yorktown Heights, NY

July 2017 - August 2018

#### Software Developer, Watson Health Cloud

- Developed Python application on another team that moved their locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap.

Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.

- Tools & Technologies: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, PyCharm, MacOS.

# UW-Madison Plasma Physics Dept., Madison, WI

Jan. 2016 - May 2017

# Scientific Programmer

# Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017